

Aman Yadav

UG Student, B.Tech CSE (2023)

PROFILE

Address A-47, New Anand Vihar Rakesh Marg Ghaziabad, Uttar Pradesh 201001

Phone Number +91-9717617021

Website

https://yadav-aman.github.io

Email Address amansy04@gmail.com

Date Of Birth 26 December 1999

Linkedin aman-yadav07

Github yadav-aman

AWARDS AND ACCOMPLISHMENTS

SNU-HCL

July Hackathon Winner 2020 **HCL**

Deans List November Shiv Nadar 2020 University

IICDC March 2019 Govt. of India

Ideonator November 2019 AIC-SNU

Toycathon June **Finalist** 2021 Govt. Of India

CERTIFICATIONS

Google IT

Automation with September **Python** Coursera

A 6 course specialization offered by Google on coursera

Deep Learning September **Specialization** 2020 Coursera

A 5 course Specialization offered by coursera.

LANGUAGES

English Hindi Fluent **Native Tongue** Punjabi **Familiar**

HOBBIES

Badminton

Travelling

Art

Coding

Digital Art and Illustrations

ABOUT ME

A self motivated student, developer and a lifelong learner with an open and inquisitive mind. I love to code, and I'm inclined towards open-source technology and cybersecurity. I am always open for new challenges and opportunities. I am a team player and always willing to step up as a leader. Some of my key strengths are:

- Hands on programming experience in Java and Python
- Commitment and determination to execute a task to completion
- Familiarity with *nix Operating systems
- Aptitude for automation, information security and software development

WORK EXPERIENCE

Surge-SNU (December 2020 - Present)

Graphic Designer

The Annual Sports Fest of Shiv Nadar University

Go Green - SNU Marketing and Design Team

(November 2020 - Present)

greener society.

Blue Circle - SNU (July 2021 - Present)

A social and environmental club which aims at a cleaner and

Volunteer

Peer support guide to help freshmen getting accustomed with the university

HackData

Volunteer

Annual Inter University tech fest of SNU

EDUCATION

(July 2019 - Present) Shiv Nadar University 8.88 CGPA **Bachelors** Computer Science & Engineering

New Era School 10 CGPA 10+2 Schooling

SKILLS

Python Java

Git Linux

C/C++ **JavaScript** HTML/CSS React

DBMS Open CV

PROJECTS

CodeForces Helper

https://github.com/yadav-aman/codeforces-helper

CLI python app to automatically extract and organize the sample test-cases of a given code-forces contest in separate directory, with cross-platform support and automatic testing of code against all the test cases.

Gesture Control Mouse

https://github.com/yadav-aman/HandTracking

Machine Learning based virtual mouse made using Open-CV to control mouse using hand tracking

Flask Based Ecommerce Site

https://github.com/yadav-aman/HCL-HackathonQ2

A fully functional flask based Ecommerce site with recommendation system.

2-3 Tree Visualizer

https://github.com/yadav-aman/TwoThreeTree

A visual representation of 2-3 Tree using JavaFX.

Voting System (May 2020 - September https://github.com/yadav-aman/CSD-

project

2020)

A voting system written in C, which uses data structures like

AVL trees and Linked List along with String processing, File Handling to handle various operations.

TODO CLI

A python CLI TODO app to organize tasks at hand.